# Syarifah Rosita Dewi

Indonesia | srositad.github.io | 089677207762 (whatsapp) | syarifahrositadewi@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Data Scientist with 4+ years of total experience in building data-intensive applications, overcoming complex architectural, and scalability issues in diverse industries. Proficient in predictive modeling, computer vision, data processing, data preparation, and data mining algorithms. Capable of creating, developing, testing, and developing highly adaptive diverse services to translate business and functional qualifications into substantial deliverables.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

# PT. Sinarmas Agro Resources and Technology, Tbk

Data Scientist

September 2021 - September 2022

- Support analysis model to improve accuracy and detect number on Odometer Truck.
- Analysis and collected data damage road for development in an app to detect damage road and normal road using machine learning and statistical analysis.
- Support analysis and collecting data on load volume detection using segmentation.
- Created a reporting analysis for user.
- Collaborate and create documentation for the developer team about the model.
- Led and collaborated with iOT dev on LiDAR System for truck load volume detection for building models on the new system.
- Do forecast analysis of CPO and PK using multiple methods for comparison.
- Led and supported DTP (Digital Talent Program) to build models of speech to text.
- Conduct analysis in the biotech area using AI Solution to help clients change manual to automatic systems in fields such as counting tray plants of ramet, detect disease root plants of ramet, measurement height of ramet and detect palm on the tree to collaborate with iOT devices.
- Do collect and preprocessing ramet image dataset.
- Generated reports on Excel and PowerPoint to conduct analysis and research.

#### Akademi-ai

Data Scientist Consultant (Freelancer)

April 2020 - December 2021

- Manage projects for the team.
- Experience designing and delivering services or solutions for which data modeling and analytics are a significant component.
- Identify/develop appropriate machine learning/data mining/text mining techniques to uncover the value of the data.
- Being teaching in the AI / Data Science area.
- Develop course material in a task force for training projects.

## **Warung Pintar**

Statistician

June 2020 - December 2020

- Researched and built a simple recommended system for elastic search based on ranking or rating products.
- Analysis data / product matching and validation to compare other marketplace with other marketplace retail.
- Route optimization for minimum fleet analysis.
- Fraud prediction analysis using machine learning.

## Moeslema

Data Scientist

September 2018 - March 2020

- Developing AI Moeslema for users to get personalized beauty products to solve their skin problems.
- Collecting, cleaning and preprocessing image dataset (person), modeling and evaluating the data.
- Ensured quality control of apps as android user testing and in collaboration with mobdev team.
- Helping create the story of the apps (flow) and help create a user interface.
- Doing user analytics and providing reports (insight from various data sources) to be conveyed to brand partnership through the business partnership team.
- Effectively communicate technical concepts about Moeslema to a non-technical user (new brand partnership).

- Research about beauty, health, and computer vision.
- Theoretical build recommended system beauty products in apps.
- Develop age detection for the feature of apps.

## PT. Coca Cola Amatil Indonesia

Data Analyst Internship

February 2019 – March 2019

- Focus on area mapping distribution routing analysis for minimum distance and minimum cost using TSP.
- Generated reports on Excel and visualized mapping for Semarang area distribution.

## **EDUCATION**

# **Islamic University of Indonesia**

BS in Statistics

Graduation Date: July 2018

- Final Projects: Deep Learning Object Detection on Video Using TensorFlow and Convolutional Neural Network.
- Publication:
  - Grouping of Provinces in Indonesia based on the Condition Cooperative using K-Means Clustering HISAS 2014 (Hokkaido Indonesian Student Association Science) Japan 2017
  - Poverty Rate Analysis of Central Java Province with K-Means Cluster Mining Method (ICASS) ITB

# **CERTIFICATES**

• Modern Computer Vision<sup>TM</sup> PyTorch, Tensorflow2 Keras & OpenCV4

Via Udemy

May 2022 - No Expired Date

• Introduction to TensorFlow for Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, and Deep Learning

Via Coursera

December 2020 - No Expired Date

#### **SKILLS & INTERESTS**

Skills: Microsoft Office (Excel, PowerPoint) | Statistical Analysis | GCP | Machine Learning & Deep Learning | Computer Vision | Data Visualization | Data Modeling | Data Preparation | Data Analysis | Data Mining | A/B Testing | SQL | Python | R

#### **LANGUAGES**

**English** 

Indonesia